ncalculators.com 2018-12-28

# ncalculators.com's Privacy Policy

  | 

## **Privacy Policy**

We take our user's privacy very seriously. If you have any questions regarding to our Privacy Policy, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@ncalculators.com).    
By using ncalculators.com's content, you agree that you accept our Terms of Service which includes this Privacy Policy & Disclaimer. If you do not want to be bound by any part of this or whole privacy policy and terms of service, please do not use, browse or access any part of ncalculators.com or any service we provide through or available on ncalculators.com.  

## **User Information Collection, Use & Sharing **

ncalculators.com gathers information directly through its interfaces such as email & feedback form and indirectly through our third party services such as Google Analytics & Google Adsense. The third party services Google Analytics & Google Adsense collectively called as Google services here. 

Under any circumstances, ncalculators.com never share any personal information to any other third party services unless it is required by law.   

**Via Feedback & Contact Us Form**

Users or visitors may required to provide personal information, such as names & email addresses when they initiate any communication through emails or through the Contact Us form available at <https://ncalculators.com/feedback.php>, otherwise, ncalculators.com never ask your personal information. Such information that we collect through contact us or feedback form kept very confidential in our servers. Our servers is located in United States and all the communications happened via SSL connections only. Further, we never collect any personal information from users under the age of 13.

We use such information to communicate back to solve your queries, inform about product announcements, events or offers. We never sell, lease or share any personal information, including names and email addresses to any third party services unless it is required by law.

**Via Website Cookies**

We use cookies to measure our users, personalize content & serving ads. Like many other websites, ncalculators.com also using HTTP Cookies, a small piece of data sent from our website & stored in the user's web browser while browsing our website, to collect the general information to measure our website visitors to ensure better user experience on this website. This general information of user activity includes but is not limited to, IP (internet protocol) addresses ([anonymous IP address for EEA users](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en)), browser types, ISPs (Internet Service Providers), entry pages, pages visited, exit pages, entry time, exit time, time you visited, demographic locations, referring websites, referring webpage, click activity & devices. Such information which is collected through the ncalculator.com's cookies is **completely anonymous** and does not identify any visitor personally. 

For analytics purpose, we use Google Analytics, a third party service to measure our visitors or user's activity within & around this website. Google Analytics may collect general information which includes but is not limited to, IP (internet protocol) addresses ([anonymous IP address for UK users](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en)), browser types, ISPs (Internet Service Providers), entry pages, pages visited, exit pages, entry time, exit time, time you visited, demographic locations, referring websites, referring webpage, click activity & devices. Please visit [Google Analytics Privacy & Security](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) to get more information about Google Analytics user's data security and privacy. To opt out Google Analytics, please visit [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

We use our third party service Google Adsense to serve [contextual & personalized (relevant) ads](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/7670013) to users. For users from EEA zone, non-personalized ads. For users from other region except EEA zone, we serve personalized ads by default. However, users can change the setting from personalized to non-personalized ads by using cookies consent interface.

Google services retain the aggregated user data for 26 months. User data beyond this period gets deleted automatically. For more information, on how Google safeguard users data, visit this URL <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

## **Remove or Withdraw Cookies Consent**

Users can control the third party website cookies by using this cookies consent interface. The Google Analytics & Google Adsense cookies can be turned ON & OFF separately by using the corresponding buttons in the interface. Users can browse or access this website with both cookies turned OFF or turned ON or either one cookies turned OFF or ON. Both the Google services cookies gets turned ON, if the cookies consent is accepted. You can withdraw such cookies consent stored in your browser at anytime by using the "**WITHDRAW**" button. All the cookies of this website can simply be removed from your browser by using the button "**Remove All Cookies**". 

## **Cookies Details  
Necessary Cookies**

  * PHPSESSID → to store the time of your session initiated with this website.
  * DO_CONSENT → to display cookies consent interface for users from EEA zone.
  * analytics-status → to store the status of Google Analytics cookies.
  * adnetwork-status → to store the status of Google Adsense cookies.
  * consent-date → to store cookies consent accepted date.
  * consent-status → to store cookies consent status.

## **Third Party Cookies Details**

NID → unique ID from Google to customize ads preference   
_ga, _gid & _gat_gtag_UA_87612639_1 → these cookies are used to measure the users. 

## **For Third Party Websites & Services**

Your dealings with advertisers and third party vendors found on or through the ncalculators.com website or any related services, including your participation in promotions, the purchase of goods, and any terms, conditions, warranties or representations associated with such activities, are solely between you and the corresponding third parties. ncalculators.com does not make any representations or warranties with respect to any goods or websites that may be obtained from such third parties, and you agree that ncalculators.com will have no liability for any loss or damage of any kind incurred as a result of any activities you undertake in connection with the use of or reliance on any content, goods, services, information or other materials available, or through such third parties, on our Website. You acknowledge that such external sites usually have their own terms and conditions, including privacy policies, over which ncalculators.com has no control and which will govern your rights and obligations with respect to the use of those websites. 

## **Policy Updates**

Please note that we may change our Privacy Policy from time to time. Users can view our latest Privacy Policy at any time by visiting: ­­­[ https://ncalculators.com/privacy-policy.html](https://ncalculators.com/privacy-policy.html)   
If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, feel free to contact us by writing to the email address [privacy@ncalculators.com](mailto:privacy@ncalculators.com)

|
